How could this have happened?!
Nasıl ölebilir?!
Lady Komurasaki!
Komurasaki-sama!
I would give anything to see you again!
Seni tekrar görmek için her şeyimi verirdim!
This isn't the oiran's procession I wanted to watch.
Görmek istediğim Oiran geçit töreni bu değildi.
Where are you taking Lady Komurasaki?!
Komurasaki-sama'yı nereye götürüyorsunuz?!
She defied Shogun Orochi.
Orochi-sama'ya karşı çıktı.
She will receive a criminal's cremation at Rasetsu Prison.
Rasetsu Hapishanesi'nde bir suçlu gibi yakılacak.
Tonoyasu's been caught?!
Tonoyasu'yu mu yakalamışlar?!
What in the world is going on?!
Neler dönüyor burada?!
To think Tonoyasu was the Witching Hour Boy!
Tonoyasu-san'ın İblis Saati Çocuğu olduğuna inanamıyorum!
The Witchin Hour Boy...
İblis Saati Çocuğu...
Night after night, the master thief stole treasures from the rich
Usta hırsız, her gece zenginlerden çaldığı serveti...
before distributing them to the poor and the vulnerable.
yoksullara ve muhtaçlara dağıtırdı.
A thief?!
Hırsız mı?!
That old fogey?
Şu eski kafalı mı?
The Witching Hour Boy...
İblis Saati Çocuğu...
The Flower Capital was abuzz with his name.
Çiçek Başkenti onun ismiyle çalkalanıyordu.
I don't get it. Wasn't he some kind of saint?
Anlayamıyorum. Aziz falan değil miydi o?
Tonoyasu!
Tonoyasu-san!
Why is everyone laughing?!
Neden herkes gülüyor?!
Your man is getting crucified!
Adamınız çarmıha geriliyor!
Is Tonoyasu really the Witching Hour Boy?!
Tonoyasu-san gerçekten İblis Saati Çocuğu mu?!
Even if it were true, it wouldn't matter.
Doğruysa bile artık fark etmez.
I remember him! It was that hair.
Onu hatırladım! O saçlar...!
Tonoyasu is an alias.
Tonoyasu onun takma adı.
Then just who is he?
O hâlde kim o?
It looks like something big is going down in the Flower Capital.
Çiçek Başkenti karışacak gibi duruyor.
Turn on the light-scroll snail.
Görüntü yansıtıcı salyangozu açın.
You know him?
Onu tanıyor musun?
Y-Yes. I know him well.
E-Evet. Çok iyi tanıyorum.
That gentleman...
O beyefendi...
He used to be one of the daimyo who served the Kozuki Clan along with Lord Oden...
Oden-sama'nın akranı, Kozuki Hanesi'ne hizmet eden daimyolardan biriydi.
His true name was...
Onun gerçek adı...
Shimotsuki...
Shimotsuki...
Lord Yasuie!
Yasuie-dono!
The daimyo of Hakumai! Yasu the Hedgehog!
Hakumai Daimyo'su, Kirpi Yasu!
He was a stern man who never smiled.
Yüzü asla gülmeyen, çok sert bir adamdı.
I didn't recognize him because he was nothing like his old self!
Eski hâlinden eser yoktu, o yüzden onu tanıyamadım!
Stop the execution!
İdamı durdurun!
I'm from Hakumai!
Ben Hakumai'liyim.
I'm glad I saw you again...!
İyi ki sizi tekrar gördüm..!
Release Lord Yasuie now, you damn bureaucrats!
Yasuie-sama'yı hemen bırakın, aşağılık memurlar!
Lord Yasuie!
Yasuie-sama!
The people haven't forgotten me yet?!
Demek halk beni hâlâ unutmamış?!
How delightful!
Çok mutlu oldum!
Hakumai is the only region in Wano with an official port.
Wano'da resmi limanı olan tek bölge Hakumai'dir.
It brings both good and bad visitors.
Hem iyi hem de kötü misafirleri buraya çeker.
Thus...
Bu nedenle...
we must have an indomitable army.
yılmaz bir ordumuz olmalı.
I'd expect nothing less from Wano's finest samurai.
Wano'nun en iyi samuraylarından daha azını bekleyemezdim.
Want a bite?
İster misin?
Are you mocking me, Oden?
Benimle alay mı ediyorsun, Oden?
Your loitering here is wearisome.
Burada aylak aylak dolaşmanızı onaylamıyorum.
At least in name, you are the shogun's son.
Sonuçta sen şogunun çocuğusun.
They threw me out. I'm not sure if they still consider me family.
Beni kovdular. Hâlâ aileden görüldüğümü sanmıyorum.
Everyone says...
Herkes bu konuyu konuşuyor.
"Oden will not be the heir to Kozuki Sukiyaki...
"Kozuki Sukiyaki gittiğinde, Oden yerini dolduramayacak...
It'll be Shogun Yasuie."
sonraki şogun, Yasuie olacak."
You idiot!
Ahmak!
Ow!
Of!
What was that for?!
Bu ne içindi?!
Don't take these idle rumors to heart!
Böyle boş söylentileri ciddiye alma!
You are the one and only successor of the Kozuki Clan!
Kozuki Hanesi'ne önderlik edecek olan sensin.
Lord Sukiyaki disowning you was just tough love.
Sukiyaki-sama'nın seni reddetmesi, tamamen senin iyiliğin içindi.
Why not show him what he wants?
Neden ona beklediği şeyi göstermiyorsun?
Yasu.
Yasu-san...
I'd rather try my luck at sea.
şansımı denizde denemeyi yeğlerim.
Why doesn't this country allow that?
Neden bu ülkede buna izin verilmiyor?
This isolationist policy... I detest these confines!
Bu tecrit politikası... Lanet olsun tüm bu kısıtlamalara!
Quiet!
Sus!
Only a true samurai is allowed selfish whims!
Sadece saygın bir savaşçının bencil kaprisleri olur!
That hurts! Where do you get off punching me?!
Çok acıtıyor! Bana vurmayı bırak!
Who do you think I am?!
Kim olduğumu sanıyorsun ki?!
You're still a nobody. Just some delinquent.
Hâlâ bir hiçsin. Sadece bir suçlusun.
It's no use, my friends! Orochi won't let me go.
Hiçbir faydası yok, dostlarım! Orochi gitmeme izin vermeyecektir!
But first, there are two things for which I must apologize.
Ama öncelikle, iki şey için özür dilemeliyim.
And I also have one thing to say to that fool Orochi!
Ayrıca o aptal Orochi'ye de söyleyeceklerim var!
Toko!
Toko!
Once I've said my piece, I'll cross to the other side with a smile on my face.
Son sözümü söyledikten sonra, yüzümde bir tebessümle öteki dünyaya göçeceğim.
Daddy!
Babacığım!
I will now state the charges against the accused.
Şimdi sanığa yöneltilen suçlamaları açıklayacağım.
This man committed theft in the Flower Capital last night.
Bu adam, dün gece başkentte hırsızlık yaptı.
How the mighty have fallen...
Nereden nereye...
Once the former daimyo of Hakumai, he now makes his living as a jester in Ebisu Town.
Eski Hakumai Daimyosu, şimdilerde Ebisu Kasabası'nda soytarılık yapıyor.
His name is Shimotsuki Yasuie!
Adı Shimotsuki Yasuie!
For the heinous crime of rebelling against Shogun Orochi in the past,
Vaktiyle Şogun Orochi'ye başkaldırmak gibi affedilmez bir suç işlediği için,
we present him as an offering to the oiran Komurasaki's grave...
onu Oiran Komurasaki'nin kabrine adak olarak sunuyor...
hereby sentencing him to an ignominious death.
ve ibretlik bir ölüme çarptırıyoruz.
Now, he has confessed...
Şimdi ise,
to being the Witching Hour Boy, a known menace to society.
toplum düzenini tehdit eden İblis Saati Çocuğu olduğunu itiraf etti.
I lied about that!
O bir yalandı!
What did you say?!
Ne dedin sen?!
I figured I was going to die, so I said that to draw attention to myself.
Öleceğimi anladım, bu yüzden dikkatleri üzerime çekebilmek için öyle söyledim.
I'm sorry about lying.
Yalan söylediğim için özür dilerim.
I'm not the hero you thought I was.
Sandığınız kahraman ben değilim.
Lord Yasuie!
Yasuie-dono!
Why did he tell such a lie?
Neden böyle bir yalan söyledi ki?
The sorrow surrounding Komurasaki's funeral has shifted its focus to Yasuie's execution.
Komurasaki'nin cenazesini saran keder, odağını Yasuie'nin idamına kaydırdı.
Drake, the Ebisu townspeople are charging into the Flower Capital!
Drake-san, Ebisu halkı Çiçek Başkenti'ne akın ediyor!
What?!
Ne?!
That man appears to be more important than we imagined.
Şu herif, tahmin ettiğimizden de önemli biri çıktı.
You can't die, Yasu!
Çiçek Başkenti Ön Kapısı
Yasu!
Yasu-san!
We'd be lost without your support!
Desteğin olmadan yok oluruz!
You don't have permission to enter the city! Go back to Ebisu Town, damn peasants!
Şehre girmeye yetkiniz yok! Ebisu'ya geri dönün, sizi pislikler!
Yasu!
Yasu-san!
The residents on the main street are raging!
Ana caddedeki halk galeyana geldi!
In the west district, too!
Batı bölgesi de karıştı!
One problem after another...
Sorun üstüne sorun.
Lord Orochi's decision to broadcast the execution via the light-scrolls may backfire.
Orochi-sama'nın idamı yayınlatma kararı, başına büyük iş açabilir.
Maintain vigilance throughout the city.
Şehir genelinde gözlerinizi dört açın.
The lord shogun is incompetent, which means his retainers have their work cut out for them.
Şogun-dono beceriksiz olunca, adamlarının işi başından aşkın oluyor.
Listen, my friends!
Dinleyin, dostlarım!
Behold, the lovely Flower Capital!
Karşınızda, görkemli Çiçek Başkenti!
The view of Wano is simply magnificent!
Wano'nun manzarası harikulade!
This landscape is the product of
Bu manzara,
generations of work by the Kozuki Clan and the common people.
Kozuki Hanesi ve halkın nesiller boyu süren emeğinin eseridir.
We take pride in it.
Gurur duymalıyız!
Hurry!
Daha hızlı!
Get a move on!
Acele edin!
He's started spouting nonsense!
Saçma sapan konuşmaya başladı!
A fool like you has no right to take credit for this beauty...
Bu güzelliği kendine pay biçmeye hiç hakkın yok...
Kurozumi Orochi!
Kurozumi Orochi!
Can you hear me, Orochi?!
Beni duyabiliyor musun, Orochi?!
There were once vast forests, grasslands...
Geniş ormanlar, çayırlar...
rivers...
nehirler...
and villages!
ve köyler!
You stained it all with your greed-spawned sludge!
Açgözlülüğünün yarattığı çamurla her şeyi kirlettin!
You're nothing but a vermin!
Bir haşereden başka bir şey değilsin!
Damn you!
Senin ben..!
Damn you, Holdem!
Holdem, seni sidikli!
How dare you set fire to my hideout!
Sığınağımı yakmaya nasıl cüret edersin!
Where are you?! Get out here!
Neredesin?! Çık ortaya!
Holdem!
Holdem!
Is that...?!
O...?!
That's enough, Lord Yasuie!
Bu kadar yeter, Yasuie-sama!
You won't be able to take it back!
Artık geri dönüşü olmayacak!
There is another thing...
Ve şimdi...
that I would like to apologize to you for.
herkese bir özür borçluyum.
Regarding the flyer with the symbol that's been making the rounds...
Son zamanlarda, ortalıkta bulmaca gibi bir şeyler dolaşıyor.
The Kozuki name's been dead twenty years.
Kozuki ismi 20 yıldır ölüydü.
We no longer have the strength to avenge them.
Artık onların intikamını alacak gücümüz yok.
I was feeling remorse for the Kozuki Clan...
Kozuki Hanesi için yaşadığım pişmanlığın verdiği his ile...
so I created that flyer!
o bulmacayı ben yarattım!
– What?!
– Ne?!
The symbol is meaningless.
O sembol mânasız.
It was...
O sadece...
just a prank!
bir şakaydı!
– What?!
– Ne?!
What the hell's he saying?!
Neler söylüyor o?!
There you are, Ashura!
İşte buradasın, Ashura.
Oh, Kin'emon! Inuarashi! This is big!
Ah, Kin'emon! Inuarashi! Buna inanamıyorum!
Look!
Bakın!
Lord Yasuie appears to have survived.
Yasuie-sama görünüşe göre hayatta kalmış.
Yes, I just found out myself.
Evet, ben de şimdi fark ettim.
It has become quite a spectacle.
Bu iş kontrolden çıkıyor.
Oden died twenty years ago.
Oden, 20 yıl önce öldüğünde...
Orochi spoke to us, the four remaining daimyo.
Orochi, geriye kalan dört daimyo ile konuştu.
"Will you serve under the Kurozumi?
"Kurozumi'ye hizmet edecek misiniz...
Or will you fight us?"
yoksa bize karşı savaşacak mısınız?"
How laughable!
Tam bi' komedi!
You owed a great debt to Oden,
Bulunduğun yeri Oden'e borçluydun...
yet you usurped the shogunate through a devious scheme!
ama şogunluğu sinsi bir planla gasp ettin!
Who would acknowledge you?!
Seni kim adam yerine koyar ki?!
The daimyo and people from each region immediately took up arms.
Bölge daimyoları ve halk vakit kaybetmeden ayaklandı.
We were unfortunately routed by the monster known as Kaido,
Ne yazık ki Kaido olarak bilinen canavar tarafından...
so Wano was consumed in flames.
bozguna uğratıldık, bu yüzden Wano da yanıp kül oldu.
I reluctantly survived and hid away in Ebisu Town.
Zalim kader işte, bir şekilde hayatta kaldım ve Ebisu Kasabası'nda saklandım.
However, it'd be a shame to die a natural death...
Ama ecelimle ölmek israf olurdu...
So, channeling my inner child, I came up with the idea for the flyer prank and gave it a shot.
Ben de içimdeki çocuğa uyup şu ilan şakasını yapmaya karar verdim.
I hope you can forgive me.
Umarım beni affedebilirsiniz.
Nevertheless, Orochi's cowardice surpassed all expectations.
Yine de Orochi'nin korkaklığı tüm beklentileri aştı.
He seems to have imprisoned innocent people simply because of a popular moon tattoo.
Sırf popüler ay dövmeleri var diye suçsuz insanları içeri tıktı.
– What?!
– Ne?!
Was it all in Shogun Orochi's mind?!
Yani hepsi Orochi-sama'nın kuruntusu muydu?!
What should we do?! We've arrested so many!
Ne yapacağız?! Çok fazla kişiyi tutukladık!
Shogun Orochi! It's in sight now!
Orochi-sama geldi!
You bastard, Yasuie!
Soktuğumun Yasuie'si!
Just wait till I fill you with lead!
Seni kurşun manyağı yapacağım!
There you are.
Demek geldin.
Long time no see, Orochi.
Uzun zaman oldu, Orochi.
Any last words, Yasuie?!
Son sözün var mı, Yasuie?!
Orochi! I suppose I do...
Orochi! Evet var...
Shall I recite the curse that has haunted you?
Sana musallat olan o laneti okuyayım mı?
"A man of such small caliber shall never know...
"Küçük bir adam...
the taste of oden in all of his life!"
asla, yiyemeyeceği bir oden'den fazlası olamayacak!"
Well, that's it.
İşte bu kadar.
Go forth... Kin'emon and the Red Scabbards.
Size bol şans diliyorum, Kin'emon ve Kızıl Kınlar.
You too, Momonosuke, the future shogun.
Ve sana da geleceğin şogunu, Momonosuke.
This effectively resets your plan!
Böylece planınız fiilen başa dönmüş oluyor!
I provided a new rendezvous point...
Rasetsu'da tutuklanan yoldaşlarımız için...
for our comrades imprisoned in Rasetsu Town.
yeni bir buluşma noktası hazırladım.
I know it's not much, but there's nothing more I can do with this life of mine.
Biliyorum pek bir şey değil ama şu ömrümle yapabileceğim başka bir şey yok.
Is he going to sacrifice himself to keep our plan alive?!
Planımızı yaşatmak için kendini feda mı edecek?!
Lord Yasuie!
Yasuie-dono!
We are forever in your debt!
Sonsuz teşekkürler!
No matter how much that coward Orochi hollers,
O korkak Orochi ne kadar bağırırsa bağırsın,
his soldiers will no longer be swayed.
askerlerinin içine kurt düştü bir kere.
A shogun shouldn't act with such fear.
Bir şogun bu kadar korkakça davranmamalı.
Stop it! They'll hear you!
Yapma! Seni duyacaklar!
Daddy!
Babacığım!
Yasu!
Yasu!
For twentyh years, no one could chop off Kaido's head!
20 yıldır Kaido'yu kimse deviremedi...
But this time...!
ama şimdi şansımız var!
Cover your children's eyes!
Çocuklarınızın gözlerini kapatın!
The last daimyo to serve the Kozuki...
Kozuki'ye hizmet eden son daimyo...
No...
Hayır...
The neighborly man of Ebisu Town is heading off to the great beyond!
Ebisu Kasabası'nın neşeli adamı öteki dünyaya göçmek üzere!
Yasuie!
Yasuie!
Let's sing as I go!
Haydi şarkı söyleyelim!
♪ Here I go! ♪
♪ İşte gidiyorum! ♪
Fire!
Ateş!
Invade Onigashima!
Onigashima'yı istila edin!
Avenge your lord!
Lordumuzun intikamını alın!
I await the good news in the afterlife!
Sonraki yaşamımda iyi haberlerinizi bekliyor olacağım!
Why would you want to steal this much money?
Neden bu kadar para çalmak isteyesiniz ki?
Lord Oden was broke!
Oden-sama meteliksiz!
If you're gonna kill us, just do it already...
Bizi öldüreceksen öldür gitsin!
you hedgehog!
Seni kirpi bozuntusu!
Damn you, Oden. You certainly know how to pick them.
Yapacağın işe, Oden. Etrafına tuhafları toplamayı iyi biliyorsun.
Listen up!
Dinleyin!
I am giving you the money you tried to steal.
Size çalmaya çalıştığınız parayı vereceğim.
– What?!
– Ne?!
Please rethink this, Lord Yasuie!
Lütfen tekrar düşünün, Yasuie-sama!
We won't be able to sustain Hakumai's finances!
Hakumai'nin ekonomisini daha fazla döndüremeyeceğiz!
You can have this too.
Tüm bunları da alabilirsiniz.
It is yours!
Hepsi sizin.
Even more money?!
Daha da fazlası mı?!
You gotta be kidding me! Is this a trap?!
Dalga geçmeyi bırak! Bu bir tür tuzak mı?!
Do you love Oden?
Oden'i seviyor musunuz?
Of course! We owe that man our lives and then some!
Elbette! Ona canımızdan fazlasını borçluyuz!
– That's right! – Absolutely!
– Aynen öyle! – Kesinlikle!
I see...
Anlıyorum.
Then take this money, make yourselves presentable, learn some manners, buy some books, and study!
O hâlde şu parayı alın, kılık kıyafetinizi düzeltin, usul erkan öğrenin ve kitap alıp kendinizi eğitin!
Having a bunch of lowlife retainers like you would only disgrace Oden!
Sizin gibi serseri hizmetkârlar Oden'i ancak rezil eder!
He is the man...
O adam...
who will one day become the shogun of Wano!
bir gün Wano'nun şogunu olacak!
Those who serve him ought to be the best samurai Wano has to offer!
Ona hizmet edenler, Wano'nun en iyi samurayları olmak zorundalar!
Of course, protecting your lord is a must.
Lordunuzu korumak sizin mutlak göreviniz.
The capital city...
Hepiniz şehrin...
No, the entire country of Wano will have you as its guardians!
hayır, tüm ülkenin koruyucuları olacaksınız!
Got it?!
Anladınız mı?!
– Lord Yasuie!
– Yasuie-dono!
Daddy!
Babacığım!
Otoko...
Otoko...
Please forgive me, Otoko...
Lütfen beni affet, Otoko.
for leaving you without a father.
Seni babasız bıraktığım için.
Daddy!
Babacığım!
Daddy! Daddy!
Babacığım! Babacığım!
That's enough! Hold your fire!
Bu kadar yeter! Ateşi kesin!
Yasu!
Yasu!
They're the peasants from Ebisu Town! Remove the from the capital!
Bunlar Ebisu'nun köylüleri! Atın şunları Başkent'ten!
Yasu!
Yasu-san!
Lord Yasuie!
Yasuie-sama!
D-Daddy!
B-Babacığım!
Daddy!
Babacığım!
D... Daddy?
B... Babacığım?
Yasu...!
Yasu..!
Are you finally dead, Yasuie?!
Sonunda öldün mü, Yasuie?!
Lord Yasuie...
Yasuie-sama...
What are they doing?
Ne yapıyor onlar?!
What...
Burada...
in the world...?
neler oluyor?
A man is dead.
Birisi öldü.
What the hell's so funny?!
Komik olan ne lan?!
My daddy is dead!
Babam öldü!
Why you little!
Seni velet...
Please wait!
Lütfen bekleyin!
They're all... crying.
Aslında... hepsi ağlıyor.
What?!
Ne?!
The people of Ebisu Town are always smiling...
Ebisu halkı hep gülümser...
because even in times of pain or sorrow...
Acı veya keder içinde olsalar bile..
you won't see it on their faces.
bunu yüzlerinde göremezsiniz.
All facial expressions other than a smile were taken away from them...
Gülümsemek dışındaki tüm yüz ifadeleri ellerinden alındı...
They can no longer do anything but laugh.
Sadece gülümseyebilirler.
It's the fault of Kaido and Orochi...
Bunların hepsi Kaido ve Orochi'nin ülkeye getirdikleri...
for bringing smile fruits here!
GÜLÜCÜK isimli meyve yüzünden!